What's wrong?
Did you bite your tongue?
Nope.
Feels like my tooth is moving.
Don't touch it.
What should I do?
Well, the new adult tooth will grow from underneath.
You don't have to worry.
Do you want me to prepare a bowl of porridge for you?
No, it'll be fine if I just eat slowly.
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことはわかんない。
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau. nanika ga chigau.
これってギセイとは違う。何かが違う。
This is different from sacrificing. Very different.
batsugeemu jan, nante omowanai.
罰ゲームじゃん、なんて思わない。
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
de, nande nanoka wakannai
で、なんでなのかわかんない。
But I'm not really sure what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo,
ちょっと釈然としないけど、
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai, ima daiji da, nantemonjanai.
きみの存在、いま大事だ、なんてもんじゃない。
Your existence is no longer so important anymore.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai.
終わらないことなんてこの世の何処にも無い。
Things that last forever don't exist anywhere in this world.
naku no ha tsurai nja, naino,
泣くのは辛いんじゃ、ないの、
Crying is a very painful thing,
ai no SWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
愛のSWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itaine.
ずっと夢みていたいネ。
How I wish my dreams could continue on and on.
motto yasashiku shitaine.
もっとやさしくしたいね。
I want to be more gentle.
kimi to iraretara, HAPPY.
きみと居られたら、HAPPY。
Just being together with you, I'm happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne.
女の子って強いね。
Girls are strong.
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne.
だけどときどき弱いね。
But at times they are weak
bokura no negai ha, HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
ぼくらの希いは、HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
Our dream is to be happy, happy, happy!
sonna hibi mo HAPPY.
そんな日々もHAPPY。
Those happy days.
JUST WANNA MAKE YOU HAPPY☆
Sign: Culture Festival
Ah, Daikichi!
Oh.
W-What are you doing?
Look, that's my drawing!
Kaga Rin
It's always your father who comes from your house.
Yup, but he's not my father.
Really? He's not?
It's not too bad.
Hey hey, Rin-chan is the best in class B at drawing.
I'm sure you can become a manga artist.
What? It's impossible.
You'll be all right.
Really?
Oh, Papa! Over here!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Such elegance, and style; he's a father?
So cool!
How nice.
He's really tall.
Hey, Sayaka-chan's father is the same age as you, 31 years old.
Are you serious?
Is that so?
What a pleasant coincidence.
Papa is a model.
What? That's amazing.
Hey, Sayaka!
Only for a few years, back when I was younger.
I think I recall seeing you in my company's item catalogue.
Oh, really?
Excuse me, can you tell me your company's name, if it's fine with you?
That's probably me!
I was under your company's care.
What a cheerful person.
How nostalgic.
Right now, I'm working as a manager at the same company.
I see.
That's a pity.
The hours and salary for a model isn't stable.
So I stopped when my daughter was born.
At the same time, I was always drinking and complaining about work.
Hey, Micchan!
Nabe-chin, long time no see.
He was my classmate. We both live around here.
His kid is also here in class A.
This is Rin-chan's father, Daikichi-san.
He's the same age as us.
Really? Nice to meet you.
Me too.
All these people have become capable of protecting children.
Daikichi!
My family runs a meat stall.
It's just at the end of the shopping district.
Oh, Rin and I frequently go there to buy croquette.
Really? I'm really glad to hear that!
Me too, I also buy it from there.
I know that.
I've made some dad-friends.
Wow!
How's that? Very tall, right?
It's so tall, wow!
In a way, this is a much bigger world.
Good afternoon.
Oh, good afternoon.
It's gotten rather cold, all of a sudden.
Yeah, and all the children seem to have gone to the gymnasium.
It would've been better if they had worn extra clothing.
Yeah.
Nitani Kouki
Wow, it's drawn really well.
Are you sure?
Well, you see, it's drawn with a lot of effort.
Hey you, everyone has gone to the gymnasium.
What? Really?
This is bad.
I'm going to be scolded by my teacher!
Seriously, boys.
So cute! How many months?
She's almost tenth months.
Isn't it great, a baby?
How nostalgic.
Speaking of which, my kid caught the flu last week.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Really? It must've been hard on you.
It's fine.
It's already that season?
Don't you have them rest for another two days after the fever subsides?
To prevent spreading?
I sent my kid back to school immediately after the fever was gone.
I guess that can't be helped.
You'll risk your job if you take too much time off.
Besides, he's mostly recovered, and the virus is gone too.
That's also true.
Furthermore, if it really does spread to others, they won't know who they caught it from.
Let's go.
Erm...
Actually, it's not that I totally don't understand what they're saying.
That's why I feel even worse.
What they said just now about affecting their jobs; I actually feel the same.
Yeah, that's true.
I start feeling anxious the moment the weather becomes colder.
But Kouki, he...
Hurry up and put on your pyjamas!
Though, when the weather turns warmer after winter,
I feel relieved.
Daikichi!
Daikichi! We're going to get our backpacks, so wait for us.
Are both of you idiots!?
Kouki, your nose!
Didn't I tell you the gym is cold, and that you need to wear extra clothes?
And also, don't run in the hallway!
Yes~!
I said, don't run!
Kouki has started growing his permanent teeth, right?
We live in an apartment building, but he still insists on tossing it to the roof.
He doesn't listen to me at all, recently.
I don't have the right to comment on this, but...
Not wearing much.
Sprinting down the stairs two steps at a time at full speed.
Gobbling down my food, and drinking my milk in one gulp.
I have to stop kids from doing the things I've done before.
It feels weird.
Did you really do all those things before, Daikichi-san?
Most boys would have done them before.
I should say, looking at Kouki reminds me of myself when I was young.
I'm sorry, but I didn't expect you to behave like that in the past.
I feel at ease after hearing that.
W-What?
What are you doing?
Walk together with Kouki.
I don't wanna~
Then, let's split into a boy's team and a girl's team.
Rin-chan's face looks slightly flushed.
What?
Rin-chan probably has a fever.
It may even become a high fever.
What!
It looks much redder than usual.
It shouldn't be influenza.
But it's still safer for the family members to wear a mask.
OK.
Isn't that great?
Yeah.
Are you full already?
Yeah, I feel something around here...
The doctor said it's stomach bug, so don't force yourself to eat.
I feel like something...
Rin!?
I-I'll go get a wash basin!
What? Rin-chan has a fever?
Call the ambulance immediately.
No, I've already taken her to the doctor and got a prescription.
But she doesn't want to eat them at all.
Her temperature is increasing, and she seems to be suffering.
You must have given her too few clothes to wear.
Talking about this now won't solve anything.
Have you tried dissolving it in fruit juice?
You used to drink it all at once, as long as I added something sweet.
I'll give it a try.
Thanks, Mom.
Come on, try it. It's really sweet.
Now, have a mouthful.
Daikichi...
Excuse us for coming here so early.
How is she doing, Rin-chan?
Sorry about that!
Can I come in?
Please do.
Daikichi! What's with your head?
It isn't the flu though...
Kouki, go over there and watch TV.
OK~
Don't make much noise.
She only just fell asleep recently.
Her temperature kept increasing, and she couldn't get to sleep.
Also, she didn't sweat at all.
Did you give her something to drink?
She should at least have a sports drink.
But she isn't drinking or eating anything.
What exactly should I do?
W-What are you doing?
You must maintain composure.
An adult has to be calm and assure the child that she will be fine.
I can't do it.
I've never seen Rin like this before.
Don't say that; you can do it!
When children really get into trouble, they'll stick close to those they think can help them.
Rin-chan will be fine as long as you're by her side.
Rin-chan.
Kouki-kun's mother.
Are you thirsty?
Do you want to try eating ice cubes?
How is it?
It feels good.
Rin! Are you awake?
Sorry, I went to the toilet.
Daikichi-san.
Oh, sorry.
You can try eating ice cubes again later.
Your stomach won't be able to take it if you eat too much at once.
OK.
The ice cubes that are freezing now are sweet and delicious.
I'm really sorry. You're going to be late for work.
Rin-chan is really fighting hard.
She'll be all right as long as you are there.
Yes, thank you very much.
Thank you too, Kouki.
My bad, I may have to take leave tomorrow, too.
Give me a call if there's anything.
Sure!
I'm sorry to trouble all of you.
What're you saying?
Don't worry, just leave everything here to us.
Arigatou.
Wanna eat something?
Yeah.
So you eat only sweet stuff after catching a cold.
I'll eat the rest later.
Sure.
You'll feel better after sleeping a while more.
Why did it have to be Rin?
This kind of cold would be nothing to me if I were the one who caught it.
Dammit, dammit!
Coming!
Daikichi! Hey~~!
Kouki!
How are you, Rin-chan?
Does it hurt anywhere?
I'm fine.
I'm going to prepare you delicious porridge now.
Her temperature started rising again from the afternoon.
It's all right.
The normal body temperature is also lower in the morning, but starts rising in the afternoon.
But she went over 39 degrees.
Note: 39°C = 102.2°F = 312.15K
OK, put all these inside the pot.
OK.
Daikichi...
Water...
It looks really tasty.
I also made some for you.
Daikichi! Rin wants water.
I got it.
Kouki, you might catch it, so don't come in, OK?
It's fine if I catch it.
How can that be fine!
Yes?
Thanks a lot.
Thank you, Kouki-kun.
Rin also feels really at ease when you're around.
Now, Rin-chan.
Have some of this.
It'll be all right.
Kouki also eats this when he is sick.
This is a special porridge that will make your illness go away.
Kouki-kun also?
Yes.
He gets better immediately after finishing eating this.
It's delicious.
Daikichi.
Rin, are you feeling better already?
Yes, I feel good.
I'm hungry.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Can you help me thank your mom for her time?
Huh?
Thank her for coming over to take care of Rin.
About that... can I go with the two of you?
That again?
According to the rules, only your mom can come and pick you up.
She caught a cold and is resting at home, my mom.
What?
For real?